# Franco Cuadros

Peru



fcuadrosr@gmail.com



+51 986760799



linkedin.com/in/franco-cuadros-44b3a0ba

### **Summary**

Software engineer specializing in programming and software development with skill in problem solving, quick learning and goal-oriented. Experience with Java and cloud web development. Analysis and development of new requirements. Knowledge of the full cycle of software development. High interest in emergent technologies. Graduated in the top 20%. Complete English proficiency.

### **Experience**



### Java Developer

#### Globant

Aug 2021 - Present (10 months +)

Implementation project for an important local bank:

Analysis and development of the new credit card back-end layer for the bank from the ground up, according to the Product Owner and Business Specialist requirements using Scrum.

APIs design and definition using OpenAPI 3.0 and SwaggerHub with Design First approach.

Programming and unit testing of several APIs, using the bank proprietary framework based on Spring, applying hexagonal architecture and reactive programming.

Database design and implementation for the credit card administrative portal.

Working remotely with direct daily communication with Business, UX, Front-end and QA teams.

Use of the following technologies:

Java 11, Spring Framework, Spring Webflux, JPA, JUnit, Mockito, R2DBC, RxJava, Azure SQL, Azure Portal, Azure Kubernetes Services, OpenAPI, SwaggerHub, Maven, Jira, Git, Bitbucket, Jenkins.

## **B** Technical Lead Developer

#### Blanco SAF

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021 (5 months)

Architectural design and development from the ground up of a new web platform suite (ERP) service-oriented (REST) using Java and Spring Framework, Hibernate and SQL for a financial enterprise. Windows Server administration, database and web application server configuration. Working in an agile environment from a remote position.



### **Freelance Software Developer**

#### Freelance

Jan 2019 - Apr 2021 (2 years 4 months)

Development of incremental software solutions for several different clients, mostly from North America and Europe, according to their requirements. Working remotely with direct communication with the clients. Use of the following technologies:

Java, Spring Framework, Javascript, JQuery, .NET Core, Amazon Web Services, Git, SQL, Android.

### Application Developer

Accenture

Aug 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Implementation project for client Banco Falabella.

Definition and analysis of solutions for client's requirements.

Programming and documenting in technical and functional level.

Participation in technical proposals for the bank's web systems and web services.

Resolution of client's incidents and bug report requirements.

Use of the following technologies:

Java, Spring, Javascript, JQuery, .NET Core, AJAX, Oracle Service Bus 12c, Oracle Weblogic, Oracle DB 11g. PL/SQL. SOAP Web Services. SVN Versioning.



### ALGI Software Developer Junior

**ALGI** 

Sep 2015 - Jul 2017 (1 year 11 months)

Development of a web platform suite (ERP) service-oriented (REST) using Java 7 and Spring Framework, Hibernate and MySQL. Support and direct communication with foreign users, mostly from China. Use of SVN and macOS. Linux server administration. Working in an agile environment from a remote position with weekly office meetings.

### **Education**



### 🚺 Universidad Peruana de Ciencias Aplicadas

Bachelor of Systems Engineering 2016 - 2020

### **CIBERTEC**

Superior degree, Computer Science 2013 - 2016

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



Advanced English - Asociacion Cultural Peruano Britanica (Britanico)

#### Skills

Java • Spring Framework • RESTful WebServices • Microservices • Oracle Database • SQL • Agile Methodologies • Microsoft Azure • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Swagger API

#### **Honors & Awards**



**Best Final Project for Programming Language Course - CIBERTEC** 

2014

- Best Final Project for Development of Mobile Applications II Course CIBERTEC 2016
- Best Final Project for Requirements Engineering Course 2017
- Maximum Score in Object Oriented Programming CIBERTEC 2014
- Maximum Score in Development of Distributed Applications Course CIBERTEC 2014